Patrick Smyth, PhD

Experience

Space Telescope Science Institute (James Webb)

August 2021 — present

Technical Training and Accessibility Consultant

- Develop accessible scientific infrastructure based on Jupyter Notebooks for <u>Space Telescope Science Institute (STScI)</u> as part of the 2022-2023 Astronomy Notebooks for All initiative
- Build web application to host technical curriculum (Python and Flask, Bulma, markdown editor in JS)
- Develop open-licensed curriculum for technical and accessibility training for researchers and administrators at STScI
- Lead technical training for Space Telescope staff and researchers

Columbia University

January 2019 — August 2021

Research Computing Specialist

- Administered a major cross-campus initiative overseen by an advisory committee of high-level scientific faculty and funded directly by a governing committee of university deans.
- Managed a team of staff, faculty, and graduate student instructors to teach over 85 events for 3000 researchers
- Planned, proposed, and implemented new programming, including a <u>Curriculum Innovation Grant</u> program, intermediate intensives on NLP and ML, and a popular <u>Python User Group</u>
- Partnered with Columbia's Data Science Institute, X (formerly Google X), and the TensorFlow team on technical trainings

Graduate Center Digital Initiatives

September 2014 — December 2018

Lead Curriculum Designer / Digital Fellow

- Led development of open technical curriculum used as the foundation for bootcamps at 13+ colleges and universities around the country (<u>DHRI initiative</u>, <u>view curriculum</u>)
- Taught 35+ <u>technical workshops</u> on data science, web development, and Python programming fundamentals
- Built web app using public geolocal data that was featured in <u>PC</u>
 <u>Magazine</u> and profiled in <u>Phi Beta Kappa</u> (<u>NEH Impact Index</u>)
- Significant contributions (or primary grant writer) for successful grants totaling over \$800,000
- Co-developed an NEH-funded cloud tool for data analysis (DH Box)

58-69 43rd Ave, Apt 2A Woodside, NY 11377 patricksmyth01@gmail.com 917-675-0925 Smythp.com github.com/smythp

Highlights

Created curriculum used at 18+ colleges and universities Taught 7+ graduate and undergraduate courses International teaching experience (Fulbright)
Managed technical training for over 3,000 researchers at Columbia University
Award-winning writer
Python programmer and data analyst (Pandas, numpy)
Extensive technical skills
Grantwriting experience

Education

PhD, English, 2021 Graduate Center, CUNY

2021 Faculty Award for Most Distinguished Dissertation Graduate Center, CUNY

Milton F. Steinhardt Memorial Fellowship Award for Best Prospectus

Certificate, Interactive Technology & Pedagogy Graduate Center, CUNY

Certified, Software Carpentry

Fulbright Fellow Berlin, 2009-2010

Press

"<u>Behind the Key — Patrick</u> <u>Smyth</u>," in Phi Beta Kappa, 2017

"Trump Budget Slashes NEH Funding: Why You Should Care," PC Magazine, 2017

View Full CV

View GitHub